Guide to the Mortar Board Honor Society records, 1936-1996.
Mortar Board Honor Society records, 1936-1996
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mortar Board Honor Society records, 1936-1996.
37-4-2199
Mortar Board (Society). Hexenkreis Chapter (Cornell University)
2.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, a minute book, an audiotape, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Early records of the organization, a national senior honor society for women. Letter and tape recorded reminiscences of Lulu S. Howard and letter from Lois Osborn, both to Marjorie E. Lasko of Ohio State University for a Mortar Board history project, 1984.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Mortar Board is a national senior honor society for women.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Early records of the organization. Includes a copy of a letter from Caroline H. Swartout to Miss Osborn about the society and a typescript four-page history, 1938. Also a minute book, 1919-1930. Letter and tape recorded reminiscences of Lulu S. Howard and letter from Lois Osborn, both to Marjorie E. Lasko of Ohio State University for a Mortar Board history project, 1984.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Mortar Board (Society). Hexenkreis Chapter (Cornell University); Cornell University--Societies, etc.
Subjects:
Women college students.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- General Mortar Board materials, 1938-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Membership; lists, 1910-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Membership; recruiting, initiating, tapping, 1950-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Meetings: minutes and agendas, 1938-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Secretary's Book, 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Conventions: reports and minutes, 1929-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters and memos: to members and officers, 1950-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1938-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Faculty citations, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Mortar Board Forum newsletters, 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Mortar Board Quarterly, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12-16)
- Cornell Alumni correspondence: profiles for directory, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, general (M.B. Alumni), 1940-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Membership list (M.B. Alumni), 1940-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Annual reports (M.B. Alumni), 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Financial material: reports and receipts, 1938-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Income tax returns (M.B. Alumni), 1949-1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Photographs of Mortar Board Graduates (4), 1941-1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Material samples and catalogues for gowns (graduation), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Cornell Alumni Info Cards: Mrs. Aaron-Mrs. Zucker, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
- Mortar Board pin: from Roberta Friedman (1), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Computer list of Mortar Board Directory Prospects, letters A-T, pp. 1-139, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
- Mortar Board, 1979-1991 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Certificates, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1966-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Membership booklet, 1982-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Red Key Society, 1941-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- The Forum, 1980-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
- Databank Material, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mortar Board Membership, 1894-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mortar Board 25th National Triennial Conference, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Alumni Records, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
- Mortar Board, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Alumni survey, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- History of Der Hexenkreis, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- B. Chapin - M.B. Alumna, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- M. Fleming - M.B. Alumna, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Mortar Board Extras, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Membership Booklets, M. B. Manual, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- M. B. Blueprint for Leadership in the '90's, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- M. B. Manual, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- M. B., Inc. National Conference, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence and Agendas (Doreen Robinson, President), 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Constitution, Membership List, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Planner, 75 Year Celebration, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Alumni List, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- M. B. Agendas, Minutes, Miscellany, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- M. B. General, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- M. B. Manual, Resume Book, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Reports, Forms, Handbooks, Miscellany, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Membership Lists, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)